Guide to the Arbovirus Research Unit, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arbovirus Research Unit, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale University, records
1950-1983
RU 410
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.5
The records consist of administrative and research files documenting the activities and operations of the Arbovirus Research Unit of the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-I (YRG 27-I), Records of Yale School of Epidemiology and Public Health.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative and research files documenting the activities and operations of the Arbovirus Research Unit of the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, Yale School of Medicine.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Department of Epidemiology and Public Health; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, circa 1950-1983; Accession 1998-A-116
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - Correspondence, various, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Y.F., Aldo Sprunger case, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lassa, correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dalcairne, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Han, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Influenza, P.R.8 Lee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emc-gd7 studies, protocols, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Demyelinating disease, mice, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hoogstraal, Ticks, also cyprees, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guinea pig immune sera, various viruses, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ger, aca, c-bh, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Filtration results, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene (A.S.T.M.H.) W and D, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Society of Tropical Medicine (A.S.T.M.) and hygiene, committee on public affairs, reports, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hoogstraal, Ticks, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 60-461, Goldfield, NJ, herpes, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 60-456, Goldfield, NJ, herpes, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Herpes, Winnipeg, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Herpes, H.F, 1955-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hol, Ewan, 1, Dr. Muller, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1361, Hooper, Dr. Marchette, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - H.P. 9, Dr. J, Hannoun, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Anslow, R., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Viliuiski, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Van Deusen, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Upa, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Vaccines, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Turkeys men, enc, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - M55 Arboviruses master, Cambridge, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Shope, Robert E., M.D., diary of, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Shope, Robert E., M.D., diary of, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - R.F. Shope, Robert E., 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - R.F. Shope, Robert E., 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - R.F. Shope, Robert E., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - R.F. Shope, Robert E., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - R.F. Shope, Robert E., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - General correspondence, N, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General correspondence, O, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence, P, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - General correspondence, R, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Trinidad Regional Virus laboratory employees, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Senegali public health, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Strengthening health delivery systems in Central and West Africa, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Health program, Senegal, book 1 (parts 1 and 2), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Health program, Senegal, book 2, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Senegal, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Senegal, Gannett-Fleming correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Senegal, Yale correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Senegal, Herbert Sacks correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Senegal, Malaria, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Senegal, schistosomiasis, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Senegal, U.S.A.I.D.-Dakar correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - B.H.W. diaries, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Basin du fleuve Sénégal, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Environmental guidelines for irrigation, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sante en Afrique Tropicale, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Syncrisis: The Dynamics of Health, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bilharzia, Niger, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mauritania health plan, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mauritania, Dams, water related diseases, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mauritania, rural health, RAMS, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Environmental program for the Senegal river basin, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Madesahel Malicounda, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mauretania health plan, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - University of Ibadan-UDP-RF report by WGD, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Assessment of RF supported programs in medical sciences at University of Ibadan, January-February 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Waksman diary, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Waksman diary, Africa, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - U.S.A.I.D., development assistance program (D.A.P.), central and West Africa, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Senegal, A.I.D., casanance, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Sahel, VI reports, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Environmental degredation in mauritania, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - O.M.V.S., A.I.D., I.D.P., P.I.D., health, April 12, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - U.S.A.I.D., D.A.P., central and West Africa, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Diary, W.G. Downs, Africa, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - W.G. Downs, diary, Senegal and Mauritania, February 22-April 9, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - OMVS, Senegal, Mali, Mauritania, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Syncrisis: The Dynamics of Health, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Senegal collections, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - O.M.V.S.I., Senegal, social services, Foltz, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - List commentée des oiseaux du Sénégal et de la gambie, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Irrigated agriculture, cost benefit analysis, Foltz, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Technical proposal, Senegal rural health project, phase II, December 15, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Prospects for primary health care in Africa, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Contribution a L'etude Epidemiologique de la Trypanosomiase Humaine Africaine au Mali, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sahel IV, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Guinea, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Senegal, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Surveillance Nutritionelle au Sahel, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Guinea, world bank, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bakel report by John Nebiker, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - U.S.A.I.D., Family Health Care Inc., Health in the Development of Senegal, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dwyer and Waksman, West Africa, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Diary, W.G. Downs, Africa, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Diary, Waksman, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bakeli second report, Diallo, S.L.A.P., 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - U.S.A.I.D., Senegal river basin project plant and animal life aspects, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Terms of reference, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Senegal rural health, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bibliography, Senegal, Mali, Mauretania, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - O.M.V.S. integrated development, David Shear, October 24, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - O.M.V.S., Senegal river development scheme, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Harmful aquatic plants in Africa and Madagascar, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Health in the Development of Senegal: Options for Research, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Senegal River Basin project, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Senegal, Nigeria, Kenya, Ethiopia, W.G. Downs, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Entente Africaine, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Africa, A Dissertation Bibliography, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Collection notre milieu Géographie, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Sahel III, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Senegal, casamance, rural development, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Senegal family planning, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Assessment of environmental effects of proposed developments in the Senegal River Basin, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Assessment of environmental effects, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Disaster in the Desert, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Assessment of environmental effects, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sahel V, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Senegal River Basin, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Assessment of environmental effects, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Assessment of environmental effects, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Assessment of environmental effects, February 21, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Sahel I, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Project paper outline, Senegal river basin, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Development assistance program (D.A.P.), central and West Africa program, February 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Synthesis, final report, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Strengthening of Health Delivery Systems (S.H.D.S.) report, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Joint meeting on health, January 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Waksman, suppressor cells in human malaria, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - G.F.C.C. report, health, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Senegal, W.H.O. report, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - U.S.A.I.D., primary health care, Senegal, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Senegal, Bakel report, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - R.F. virus program, Belem, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Progress reports (part 1 and 2), 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
  - Seminar on rift valley fever, Geneva, April 22-24, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - U.S.A.I.D., P.I.D., W.G. Downs, April 2, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Senegal, health report, Gannett-Fleming, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The nineteenth joint committee meeting, U.S.-Japan cooperative medical science program, July 20, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)